<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog | Qian Lab</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/tag/blog/</link><atom:link href="https://qianlab.github.io/tag/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>blog</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://qianlab.github.io/media/icon_hu2d133e36a3bc1d258e5bb52f2c61da77_6522_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>blog</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/tag/blog/</link></image><item><title>Autonomous Lighting Audits</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/autonomous-lighting-audits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/autonomous-lighting-audits/</guid><description>&lt;p>We developed a robot that automatically finds lights in a building using a camera and identifies their types using a spectrometer. The robot localizes itself and creates a map of the building through Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM) using a distance sensor. Developed wih C++ using OpenCV on the ROS platform. [&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1QDfSND6hYo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Video&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1x_Wfi2md0A" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Demo&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://qianlab.github.io/papers/Spring2016ReportPlus.pdf">Report&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://qianlab.github.io/papers/AggiE_ChallengePoster.pdf">Poster&lt;/a>].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="team-composition">Team Composition&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This was an important experience for me, as it was in this team that I met someone who was really passionate in doing research. He would ultimately influence my passion to do research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Lesson Without Pain is Meaningless</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/a-lesson-without-pain-is-meaningless/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 08:22:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/a-lesson-without-pain-is-meaningless/</guid><description>&lt;p>“A lesson without pain is meaningless”. I have always heeded that saying throughout my life. However, only after my experiences in the summer and fall of 2014 could I begin to understand the gravity of that phrase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Entering Texas A&amp;amp;M University in fall of 2013, I thought I could achieve anything. I was determined to start researching under a professor, volunteer or intern for a job in my field, and find a scholarship to lighten my parents’ burden in funding my out-of-state tuition. However, none of these had happened to my expectations. Although I volunteered as a web designer, the position was not what I had expected, working alone and requiring a lot of trial and error to get anything done. Even though I searched for a research position since fall of 2013, I had no luck in getting one. To top it all off, all of my scholarship applications got rejected and I was still burdening my parents’ with my expensive tuition as of summer of 2014.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With these problems in my mind, the summer of 2014 was a very depressing period for me. Despite working hard and maintaining a perfect GPA, none of the great things I dreamt of came to fruition. I became disillusioned about life. Without any willpower left, I spent most of my summer alone in my apartment wasting my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One day, I was surprised by a call from my brother, who had gone to California for an internship. He asked me if I wanted to travel there to spend time with him. Without anything to do in College Station, I accepted his offer without hesitation and flew there the following week. However, we had only spent one day together until we started arguing. In hindsight, I realize that I was the one who started it because I was unable to wake up to the travel itinerary we had set beforehand. Fueled by my depression, the fight was one of the worst fights I had with my brother. I finally decided to part ways with him and traveled on my own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traveling alone, I didn’t know what to do. I knew I had nothing to do back in College Station, but I was not sure what to do alone in California. I started walking. I’m not sure where I was going but I knew I couldn’t stay in the same place forever. Unknown to me at the time, this was one of the most important decisions in my life. Walking from one city to the next, I had time to think about my life and got to meet very interesting people along the way, renewing my determination and my point of view on life. With my willpower rekindled, I decided to take a train back to College Station.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in College Station for my fall term, I had managed to get a research position on a topic I was interested in. I knew then that I was on the right track. However, research wasn’t as simple as I had initially thought. It took up a lot of my time and although it was very interesting, I was more concerned about the out-of-state tuition my parents still had to cover. I thought about dropping the research position and get a paying job in the library to help my parents, but decided against it, believing that I was still doing the right thing with my research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, I made the right decision. The department of Electrical and Computer Engineering was offering scholarships to undergraduates conducting research. I applied for this program with my research and received a scholarship which qualified for instate tuition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have learned a lot going through these challenges. I gained resilience, to always stand strong in the face of overwhelming odds. I learned patience. I realize that when things didn’t go my way, I got impatient and that caused my depression. Finally, I learned humility. I couldn’t have achieved anything without my friends and family, even my brother, who drove me to contemplate about my life while traveling alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s no such thing as a painless lesson. For you can’t gain anything without sacrificing something else in return. However, once you have endured that pain and overcome it, you’ll now find that you have a heart strong enough to overcome any obstacle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My First Experience as An Undergraduate Researcher</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/first-experience/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/first-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p>In fall of 2014, I conducted research under Dr. Robin Murphy. This research was in the field of emergency informatics. In particular, I was tasked with designing an Augmented Reality (AR) interface for Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) imagery. This AR interface, called AerialAR, would label locales such as schools or hospitals in images or videos received from a UAV. This is important for disaster responders, as they needed the ability to remotely determine mission relevant locations such as schools which may need evacuating or hospitals where victims may be transported.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had never conducted research before so I was slightly anxious to start. In hindsight, research was very difficult for me. Along with my courses, research took up so much of my time that I hardly had any left to relax in the weekend. This is because the research demanded that I create a new set of equations based on geometric relations between the UAV and the locations in the imagery. This took a lot of study in the nature of optics, motion tracking, aviation terminology, and geo-positioning conventions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, I successfully implemented the interface and even submitted my findings to the CHI 2015 conference in South Korea. More importantly, I gained valuable experience as an engineer and as a person. Firstly, I gained a good work ethic. Throughout the progress of my research, I would periodically keep my professor updated with my findings. This required me to work hard every day in order to show significant results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Secondly, I learned good time management. This is important for me, as with my course load at the time, I had barely enough time to finish any of my work. Initially, I would have to stay up very late at night to complete my homework, finish my projects, and do my research. However, after coping with the work load, I learned to manage my time well. With good time management, I acquired a new perspective on responsibility. I now understand that being responsible sometimes calls for sacrificing a lot of recreational time to finish work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also obtained good learning habits. Since my research required a lot of prior knowledge, I had to study many things in many different fields. Learning skills are essential for research, but also throughout life as well. I realize now that, similar to research, life is a journey of continuous learning. I noticed this as I would often receive ideas for my research from ordinary phenomena in everyday life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Above all, I got to help people with real life problems using the skills that I know. This not only increased my determination in the field I’m studying, but also gave me a new perspective on life. I know now that life will be brighter when everyone is willing to help each other towards a common good.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>