<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts | Qian Lab</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/</link><atom:link href="https://qianlab.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Posts</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://qianlab.github.io/media/icon_hu2d133e36a3bc1d258e5bb52f2c61da77_6522_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Posts</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/</link></image><item><title>Frank Stanford's New Editable Website with Meteor</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/frank-stanford/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/frank-stanford/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have recently developed a Content Management System (CMS) from scratch specifically made for Frank&amp;rsquo;s artwork, travel pictures, and writing. I designed his website from scratch using barebones frontend/backend libraries as a challenge. [&lt;a href="http://frankstanford.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Website&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://github.com/ardywibowo/FrankCMS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Source Code&lt;/a>].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frank was a professor in sociology in College Station who has a lot of artwork, writing, and travel photos. His home was practically a museum! He was looking to update his previous website, as it had become outdated. It didn&amp;rsquo;t support different viewports (tablets and phones) and it was a total pain to edit/add items to his website (he had to hire a person to do it for him).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The requirements for his website were particularly demanding. In addition to being responsive and working with different screen sizes, it also had to be editable. Moreover, the website was a sort of niche thing for Frank, so he didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spent a lot of money maintaining it. Finally, Frank wanted the ability to edit the website by himself, so the editing interface needed to be beautiful and fool-proof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not finding a simple solution for the above requirements, this led me to develop a website and a CMS from scratch. Here are the requirements I laid out in building this website:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Editable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dynamic/Responsive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports different screen sizes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modern/minimalistic style&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easy editing user interface&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In hindsight, the requirements were very demanding to pull off compared to the commission he gave me :P. However, I enjoyed the entire process and I have become very comfortable with the entire process of making web apps fullstack.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="main-framework">Main Framework&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The main framework I used for this project is Meteor. This is an all-in-one framework that supports frontend and backend development. I used the Meteor Angular version of this framework and wrote it primarily in TypeScript.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is very useful if you want to quickly develop a web app that supports common features such as user accounts, reactive updates, database storage, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="front-end">Front End&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Angular 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I used Angular due to its support for modular components. Arguably, I read that React has the same features. However, I am more familiar with Angular&amp;rsquo;s syntax from previous experience. Moreover, Angular officially supports Material Design templates.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Material 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In this project, I wanted to go for a minimalistic design with primarily black and white colors to contrast the colorful pictures Frank has. In my opinion, Material design achieves this effect quite naturally.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bourbon Neat&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Bourbon Neat is a great tool for general purpose CSS commands such as creating columns, assigning animations, and adjusting element proportions. It is style agnostic unlike Bootstrap which makes it less redundant when used with Material Design.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="back-end">Back End&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>MongoDB&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I used MongoDB for the database. It is very nice to get a new app up and running quickly. Adding new fields is as simple as just changing the model code in one file. Deployment wasn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult either, due to Meteor&amp;rsquo;s support of this database.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>RxJS&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>RxJS is used to support reactive updates between backend and frontend. It is very cool to see the web app update by itself on one window when you change something in another. All without any browser refresh! Meteor&amp;rsquo;s support for this framework was also good, although it takes some getting used to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially strange concepts to grasp are observables, which are like promises but you need to code them just right to make it work.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>NginX&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>NginX is used to run the web app during deployment. To be honest, the entire DevOps process was a complete pain. Thankfully, a lot of tutorials help you on this issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="hosting-service">Hosting Service&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I used &lt;strong>Digital Ocean&lt;/strong> to host the web app on Ubuntu Linux 14.04. It is very cheap for the quality. In fact, I think it may be the cheapest. No fluff and nothing you don&amp;rsquo;t need. In fact, due to many great free software, anything you need to track your website can be installed from the Terminal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="screenshots">Screenshots&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An example of the main view of the dashboard is shown below&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://qianlab.github.io/img/frank-stanford/frank-edit-menu.png" alt="Frank Stanford Dashboard">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When an artwork is clicked on the dashboard, a modal is presented and we can edit it on the spot:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://qianlab.github.io/img/frank-stanford/frank-artwork-edit.png" alt="Frank Stanford Edit Artwork">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Adding and removing artwork to an album is done through a list images in that category/album:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://qianlab.github.io/img/frank-stanford/frank-add-artwork.png" alt="Frank Stanford Add To Album">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dropdown menu that displays album contents also contain album edit features:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://qianlab.github.io/img/frank-stanford/frank-edit-album.png" alt="Frank Stanford Album Edit">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ranch Hand: Monitoring Livestock in an Open Field</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/ranch-hand/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/ranch-hand/</guid><description>&lt;p>Final senior design project sponsored by Texas Instruments. I created a web app that connects with a mesh network Internet of Things (IoT) through Amazon Web Service (AWS). [&lt;a href="https://qianlab.github.io/papers/ranch-hand.pdf">Report&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://github.com/ardywibowo/RanchHand" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Source Code&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GD-po7wXn5k" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Video&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EMdEP-M_pK0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jason Barn&lt;/a>].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="team-composition">Team Composition&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The team consisted of 4 people:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Jeff Bartlett: Mesh Network Subsystem&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Connor Furqueron: Power Subsystem&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Charles Anderson: Microcontroller Subsystem&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Qian Lab: Data Analysis/App Development&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the following video, I have laid out the general procedure of the data processing part of this project. It mainly consists of data generation, optimal sensor placement, and trilateration algorithm.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GD-po7wXn5k" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>An example of the main view of the web app is shown below:
&lt;img src="https://qianlab.github.io/img/ranch-hand-main.png" alt="Ranch Hand Main Web App View">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the end, despite team difficulties, we finished an interesting IoT application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is a cool advertisement video/movie of our project. To be honest, the video doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain a lot of technical merit, but I would be wrong if I said that it isn&amp;rsquo;t amazing. Enjoy :).&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EMdEP-M_pK0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Visual Saliency Test</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/visual-saliency-test/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/visual-saliency-test/</guid><description>&lt;p>My friend had recently asked me to help him with benchmarking this visual saliency method. I thought that the results were cool and decided to post it here. &lt;a href="https://graphics.ethz.ch/~perazzif/saliency_filters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The project page with code + paper is here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://qianlab.github.io/saliency-results.png" alt="Federico Image Saliency Results ">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From my understanding, visual saliency captures the subjective &amp;ldquo;attention&amp;rdquo; that a human would have when shown a certain picture. For example, we are attracted towards more &amp;ldquo;foreground&amp;rdquo; objects rather than background objects, objects that have stark contrasts, sharp textures, etc. Briefly reading the paper, Perazzi achieves this by constructing a &amp;ldquo;uniqueness&amp;rdquo; measure on each section in the entire image. Sections/superpixels are divided with K-means clustering. Pretty neat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone Reconstruction from Ultrasound Imagery</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/bone-reconstruction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/bone-reconstruction/</guid><description>&lt;p>I constructed a 3D representation of bone structure from ultrasound images. The ultrasound images were denoised using a Gabor filter based Generalized Linear Model (GLM) trained on a ground truth cross-section of bone image. [&lt;a href="https://github.com/ardywibowo/BoneReconstruction" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Code&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://qianlab.github.io/papers/GaborBone.pdf">Report&lt;/a>].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3></description></item><item><title>Autonomous Lighting Audits</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/autonomous-lighting-audits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/autonomous-lighting-audits/</guid><description>&lt;p>We developed a robot that automatically finds lights in a building using a camera and identifies their types using a spectrometer. The robot localizes itself and creates a map of the building through Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM) using a distance sensor. Developed wih C++ using OpenCV on the ROS platform. [&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1QDfSND6hYo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Video&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1x_Wfi2md0A" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Demo&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://qianlab.github.io/papers/Spring2016ReportPlus.pdf">Report&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://qianlab.github.io/papers/AggiE_ChallengePoster.pdf">Poster&lt;/a>].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="team-composition">Team Composition&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This was an important experience for me, as it was in this team that I met someone who was really passionate in doing research. He would ultimately influence my passion to do research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MasjidPay: News, Events, and Donations from your Local Religious Institution</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/masjid-pay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/masjid-pay/</guid><description>&lt;p>I helped my friend&amp;rsquo;s startup company developing an app for news and donations from local religious institutions. [&lt;a href="https://masjidpay.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Website&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/masjidpay/id1109868571?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Store&lt;/a>] [&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.abangfadli.masjidpay&amp;amp;hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Android&lt;/a>].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3></description></item><item><title>A Lesson Without Pain is Meaningless</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/a-lesson-without-pain-is-meaningless/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 08:22:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/a-lesson-without-pain-is-meaningless/</guid><description>&lt;p>“A lesson without pain is meaningless”. I have always heeded that saying throughout my life. However, only after my experiences in the summer and fall of 2014 could I begin to understand the gravity of that phrase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Entering Texas A&amp;amp;M University in fall of 2013, I thought I could achieve anything. I was determined to start researching under a professor, volunteer or intern for a job in my field, and find a scholarship to lighten my parents’ burden in funding my out-of-state tuition. However, none of these had happened to my expectations. Although I volunteered as a web designer, the position was not what I had expected, working alone and requiring a lot of trial and error to get anything done. Even though I searched for a research position since fall of 2013, I had no luck in getting one. To top it all off, all of my scholarship applications got rejected and I was still burdening my parents’ with my expensive tuition as of summer of 2014.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With these problems in my mind, the summer of 2014 was a very depressing period for me. Despite working hard and maintaining a perfect GPA, none of the great things I dreamt of came to fruition. I became disillusioned about life. Without any willpower left, I spent most of my summer alone in my apartment wasting my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One day, I was surprised by a call from my brother, who had gone to California for an internship. He asked me if I wanted to travel there to spend time with him. Without anything to do in College Station, I accepted his offer without hesitation and flew there the following week. However, we had only spent one day together until we started arguing. In hindsight, I realize that I was the one who started it because I was unable to wake up to the travel itinerary we had set beforehand. Fueled by my depression, the fight was one of the worst fights I had with my brother. I finally decided to part ways with him and traveled on my own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traveling alone, I didn’t know what to do. I knew I had nothing to do back in College Station, but I was not sure what to do alone in California. I started walking. I’m not sure where I was going but I knew I couldn’t stay in the same place forever. Unknown to me at the time, this was one of the most important decisions in my life. Walking from one city to the next, I had time to think about my life and got to meet very interesting people along the way, renewing my determination and my point of view on life. With my willpower rekindled, I decided to take a train back to College Station.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in College Station for my fall term, I had managed to get a research position on a topic I was interested in. I knew then that I was on the right track. However, research wasn’t as simple as I had initially thought. It took up a lot of my time and although it was very interesting, I was more concerned about the out-of-state tuition my parents still had to cover. I thought about dropping the research position and get a paying job in the library to help my parents, but decided against it, believing that I was still doing the right thing with my research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, I made the right decision. The department of Electrical and Computer Engineering was offering scholarships to undergraduates conducting research. I applied for this program with my research and received a scholarship which qualified for instate tuition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have learned a lot going through these challenges. I gained resilience, to always stand strong in the face of overwhelming odds. I learned patience. I realize that when things didn’t go my way, I got impatient and that caused my depression. Finally, I learned humility. I couldn’t have achieved anything without my friends and family, even my brother, who drove me to contemplate about my life while traveling alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s no such thing as a painless lesson. For you can’t gain anything without sacrificing something else in return. However, once you have endured that pain and overcome it, you’ll now find that you have a heart strong enough to overcome any obstacle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My First Experience as An Undergraduate Researcher</title><link>https://qianlab.github.io/post/first-experience/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qianlab.github.io/post/first-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p>In fall of 2014, I conducted research under Dr. Robin Murphy. This research was in the field of emergency informatics. In particular, I was tasked with designing an Augmented Reality (AR) interface for Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) imagery. This AR interface, called AerialAR, would label locales such as schools or hospitals in images or videos received from a UAV. This is important for disaster responders, as they needed the ability to remotely determine mission relevant locations such as schools which may need evacuating or hospitals where victims may be transported.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had never conducted research before so I was slightly anxious to start. In hindsight, research was very difficult for me. Along with my courses, research took up so much of my time that I hardly had any left to relax in the weekend. This is because the research demanded that I create a new set of equations based on geometric relations between the UAV and the locations in the imagery. This took a lot of study in the nature of optics, motion tracking, aviation terminology, and geo-positioning conventions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, I successfully implemented the interface and even submitted my findings to the CHI 2015 conference in South Korea. More importantly, I gained valuable experience as an engineer and as a person. Firstly, I gained a good work ethic. Throughout the progress of my research, I would periodically keep my professor updated with my findings. This required me to work hard every day in order to show significant results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Secondly, I learned good time management. This is important for me, as with my course load at the time, I had barely enough time to finish any of my work. Initially, I would have to stay up very late at night to complete my homework, finish my projects, and do my research. However, after coping with the work load, I learned to manage my time well. With good time management, I acquired a new perspective on responsibility. I now understand that being responsible sometimes calls for sacrificing a lot of recreational time to finish work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also obtained good learning habits. Since my research required a lot of prior knowledge, I had to study many things in many different fields. Learning skills are essential for research, but also throughout life as well. I realize now that, similar to research, life is a journey of continuous learning. I noticed this as I would often receive ideas for my research from ordinary phenomena in everyday life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Above all, I got to help people with real life problems using the skills that I know. This not only increased my determination in the field I’m studying, but also gave me a new perspective on life. I know now that life will be brighter when everyone is willing to help each other towards a common good.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>